<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on FOSS Trading</title>
    <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on FOSS Trading</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disclosures</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/disclosures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/disclosures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;amazon&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;csi-data&#34;&gt;CSI Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We receive an affiliate commission when a reader signs up for a CSI data package via a referring link from this site and/or using the &amp;ldquo;FOSS&amp;rdquo; coupon code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how this site uses their &amp;lsquo;Personally Identifiable Information&amp;rsquo; (information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context). Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-we-use-cookies&#34;&gt;Do we use &amp;lsquo;cookies&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer&amp;rsquo;s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site&amp;rsquo;s or service provider&amp;rsquo;s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use cookies to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep track of advertisements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser&amp;rsquo;s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you turn cookies off, Some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly. It won&amp;rsquo;t affect the user&amp;rsquo;s experience that make your site experience more efficient and may not function properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;third-party-disclosure&#34;&gt;Third-party disclosure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it&amp;rsquo;s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others&#39; rights, property or safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;third-party-links&#34;&gt;Third-party links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;google&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s advertising requirements can be summed up by &lt;a href=&#34;http://google%27s%20advertising%20principles/&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Advertising Principles&lt;/a&gt;. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google&amp;rsquo;s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opting out:
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;can-spam-act&#34;&gt;CAN SPAM Act&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not collect your email address. If you choose to share a post via email, Google&amp;rsquo;s Blogger service will ask your and the recipient&amp;rsquo;s email addresses, but we do not collect that information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;contacting-us&#34;&gt;Contacting Us&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:josh.m.ulrich@gmail.com&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions regarding this privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quantmod for enterprise</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/page/enterprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tidelift is working with the maintainers of quantmod and thousands of other open source projects to deliver commercial support and maintenance for the open source dependencies you use to build your applications. Save time, reduce risk, and improve code health, while paying the maintainers of the exact dependencies you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enterprise-ready-open-source-softwaremanaged-for-you&#34;&gt;Enterprise-ready open source software—managed for you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tidelift Subscription is a managed open source subscription for application dependencies covering millions of open source projects across JavaScript, Python, Java, PHP, Ruby, .NET, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your subscription includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security updates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidelift’s security response team coordinates patches for new breaking security vulnerabilities and alerts immediately through a private channel, so your software supply chain is always secure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Licensing verification and indemnification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidelift verifies license information to enable easy policy enforcement and adds intellectual property indemnification to cover creators and users in case something goes wrong. You always have a 100% up-to-date bill of materials for your dependencies to share with your legal team, customers, or partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance and code improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidelift ensures the software you rely on keeps working as long as you need it to work. Your managed dependencies are actively maintained and we recruit additional maintainers where required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package selection and version guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We help you choose the best open source packages from the start—and then guide you through updates to stay on the best releases as new issues arise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roadmap input&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a seat at the table with the creators behind the software you use. Tidelift’s participating maintainers earn more income as their software is used by more subscribers, so they’re interested in knowing what you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tooling and cloud integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidelift works with GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket, and more. We support every cloud platform (and other deployment targets, too).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end result? All of the capabilities you expect from commercial-grade software, for the full breadth of open source you use. That means less time grappling with esoteric open source trivia, and more time building your own applications—and your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
