<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LSPM on FOSS Trading</title>
    <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/tags/lspm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LSPM on FOSS Trading</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 13:38:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.fosstrading.com/tags/lspm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Timely Portfolio: LSPM Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/05/timely-portfolio-lspm-examples-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 13:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/05/timely-portfolio-lspm-examples-comments/</guid>
      <description>Josh I have sennt a mail to your gmail address. P&amp;hellip; Chris - May 5, 2011Josh
I have sennt a mail to your gmail address. Please confirm that you have received it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timely Portfolio: LSPM Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/05/timely-portfolio-lspm-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 13:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/05/timely-portfolio-lspm-examples/</guid>
      <description>Timely Portfolio has been doing some interesting work with Ralph Vince&amp;rsquo;s Leverage Space Model via the LSPM R package. Here&amp;rsquo;s a short list of his most recent LSPM-related posts:
 The Leverage Space Trading Model Bond Market as a Casino Game Part 1 Bond Market as a Casino Game Part 2 Slightly Different Use of Ralph Vince’s Leverage Space Trading Model Another Use of LSPM in Tactical Portfolio Allocation  I encourage those of you who are interested in LSPM and/or R to check out his blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Space Indexes Announced</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/04/leverage-space-etfs-announced-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/04/leverage-space-etfs-announced-comments/</guid>
      <description>Unless I&amp;rsquo;m misreading, the announcement is of &amp;hellip; Steve - Jun 4, 2011Unless I&amp;rsquo;m misreading, the announcement is of the launch of indices that could potentially underly ETFs, rather than the launch of ETFs themselves.
Steve, very good catch. Thanks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Space Indexes Announced</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/04/leverage-space-etfs-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/04/leverage-space-etfs-announced/</guid>
      <description>PRESS RELEASE
 The Leverage Space Portfolio (LSP) strategy seeks to maximize the probability of equity portfolio profitability by employing a risk-control process focused on capital preservation and drawdown management. Compared to a traditional buy-and-hold portfolio, an LSP-based portfolio aims for more consistent returns with lower risk.
The indexes, scheduled to be launched in the second half of 2011, can serve as the basis of both passive and active investment funds, including exchange-traded funds, mutual funds, and institutional accounts, around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Opportunity Analysis: Houston</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/03/risk-opportunity-analysis-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2011/03/risk-opportunity-analysis-houston/</guid>
      <description>I will be attending Ralph Vince&amp;rsquo;s risk-opportunity analysis workshop in Houston this weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be in town Friday-Monday. Drop me a note if you&amp;rsquo;re in the area and would like to meet for coffee / drinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Opportunity Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/11/risk-opportunity-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 09:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/11/risk-opportunity-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I will be attending Ralph Vince&amp;rsquo;s risk-opportunity analysis workshop in Tampa this weekend. Drop me a note if you&amp;rsquo;re in the area and would like to meet for coffee / drinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margin Constraints with LSPM</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/08/margin-constraints-with-lspm-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 23:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/08/margin-constraints-with-lspm-comments/</guid>
      <description>Josh Thank you for providing the LSPM package - I&amp;hellip; Chris - Apr 2, 2011Josh
Thank you for providing the LSPM package - I would not have been able to experiment with using LSPM if I could not use the package. I would like to confirm two things:
 the maxUnits function has not been built in to the LSPM package - correct? what should one do if using leverage is not an option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margin Constraints with LSPM</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/08/margin-constraints-with-lspm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 23:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/08/margin-constraints-with-lspm/</guid>
      <description>When optimizing leverage space portfolios, I frequently run into the issue of one or more f$ ([Max Loss]/f) being less than the margin of its respective instrument. For example, assume the required margin for an instrument is $500, f$ is $100, and $100,000 in equity. The optimal amount to trade is 1,000 shares ($100,000/$100). However, that would require $500,000 in equity, while you only have $100,000. What do you do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Probability of Drawdown</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/06/estimating-probability-of-drawdown-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 20:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/06/estimating-probability-of-drawdown-comments/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for another great post Josh. I&amp;rsquo;ve looke&amp;hellip; Ralph Vince - Jun 2, 2010Thanks for another great post Josh. I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at this at length. Remember &amp;ndash; the way you are calculating probability of drawdown, RD, is on a sample and replacement basis where the probabilities associated at each T to the horizon are unchanged. Thus, if, say, a large loss is seen at time T = t, the probablity of seeing that same large loss, in succession (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Probability of Drawdown</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/06/estimating-probability-of-drawdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 20:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/06/estimating-probability-of-drawdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve shown several examples of how to use LSPM&amp;rsquo;s probDrawdown function as a constraint when optimizing a leverage space portfolio. Those posts implicitly assume the probDrawdown function produces an accurate estimate of actual drawdown. This post will investigate the function&amp;rsquo;s accuracy.
Calculation Notes:
To calculate the probability of drawdown, the function traverses all permutations of the events in your lsp object over the given horizon and sums the probability of each permutation that hits the drawdown constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM Joint Probability Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/05/lspm-joint-probability-tables-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 22:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/05/lspm-joint-probability-tables-comments/</guid>
      <description>Josh, If I may comment: The joint probabilities ta&amp;hellip; Ralph Vince - May 3, 2010Josh, If I may comment:
The joint probabilities table (&amp;ldquo;jpt&amp;rdquo;) ultimately should encompass and be a proxy for all potential risk for the next period.
In other words, frequently, in attempting to articulate &amp;ldquo;risk,&amp;rdquo; we see the argument that it is more than mere variance. That there is liquidity risk, there is counter-party risk, this risk and that risk, and there is a notion that risk posses many facets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM Joint Probability Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/05/lspm-joint-probability-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 22:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/05/lspm-joint-probability-tables/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received several requests for methods to create joint probability tables for use in LSPM&amp;rsquo;s portfolio optimization functions. Rather than continue to email this example to individuals who ask, I post it here in hopes they find it via a Google search. ;-)
I&amp;rsquo;m certain there are more robust ways to estimate this table, but the code below is a start&amp;hellip;
&amp;lsquo;x&amp;rsquo; is a matrix of market system returns
&amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; is the number of bins to create for each system</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on LSPM from R/Finance 2010</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/thoughts-on-lspm-from-rfinance-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 22:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/thoughts-on-lspm-from-rfinance-2010/</guid>
      <description>I just got back from R/Finance 2010 in Chicago. If you couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it this year, I strongly encourage you to attend next year. I will post a more comprehensive review of the event in the next couple days, but I wanted to share some of my notes specific to LSPM.
 How sensitive are optimal-f values to the method used to construct the joint probability table? Is there an optimizer better suited for this problem (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximum Probability of Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/maximum-probability-of-profit-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/maximum-probability-of-profit-comments/</guid>
      <description>Josh, Thanks for another great explanation. I migh&amp;hellip; Ralph Vince - Apr 5, 2010Josh, Thanks for another great explanation. I might point out to that it is not just the optimization algorithms used, but in the case of mazimizing for greatest probability of profit, there are many posssible optimal sets (f1,..,fn,z+,z-). There are multiple sets which will result in an equivalent (and highest) probability of profit.
-Ralph Vince
If I understand the optimization problem correctly, I think it may be possible to achieve similar results in just minutes of computation with a different optimization approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximum Probability of Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/maximum-probability-of-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 10:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/04/maximum-probability-of-profit/</guid>
      <description>To continue with the LSPM examples, this post shows how to optimize a Leverage Space Portfolio for the maximum probability of profit. The data and example are again taken from The Leverage Space Trading Model by Ralph Vince.
These optimizaitons take a very long time. 100 iterations on a 10-core Amazon EC2 cluster took 21 hours. Again, the results will not necessarily match the book because of differences between DEoptim and Ralph&amp;rsquo;s genetic algorithm and because there are multiple possible paths one can take through leverage space that will achieve similar results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM with snow</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-with-snow-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 17:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-with-snow-comments/</guid>
      <description>Hi Joshua! Could you tell me how to calculate prob&amp;hellip; senyai - Apr 5, 2010Hi Joshua! Could you tell me how to calculate probability of drawdown using martingale exponents? I do not want to optimize anything, just calculate dd like Vince did at 173 page. My code:
-&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;
port &amp;lt;- lsp(trades,probs, f=c(0.085,0.015,0.129), z = c(-0.76, -0.992, 0.0))
probDrawdown(port,0.8,12,13)
-&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;
This code shows me value 0.0001982222, but Vince says his dd is 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM with snow</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-with-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 17:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-with-snow/</guid>
      <description>My last post provided examples of how to use the LSPM package. Those who experimented with the code have probably found that constrained optimizations with horizons &amp;gt; 6 have long run-times (when calc.max &amp;gt;= horizon).
This post will illustrate how the snow package can increase the speed of the probDrawdown and probRuin functions on computers with multiple cores. This yields nearly linear improvements in run-times relative to the number of cores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-examples-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 15:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-examples-comments/</guid>
      <description>Hi Josh I am trying to replicate the results on p&amp;hellip; Chris - Nov 2, 2011Hi Josh
I am trying to replicate the results on page 87 (as mentioned in your post above) of the LSPM book. I do the following:
&amp;gt; data(port)
&amp;gt; DEctrl &amp;lt;- list(NP=30, itermax=100)
&amp;gt; res &amp;lt;- optimalf(port, control=DEctrl)
The result is :
Iteration: 100 bestvalit: -1.293917 bestmemit: 1.000000 0.000000 0.857813
Page 87 reads:
MktSysA 0.307</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSPM Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 15:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fosstrading.com/2010/01/lspm-examples/</guid>
      <description>I have received several requests for additional LSPM documentation over the past couple days and a couple months ago I promised an introduction to LSPM.
In this long-overdue post, I will show how to optimize a Leverage Space Portfolio with the LSPM package. Please use the comments to let me know what you would like to see next.
Some copious notes before we get to the code:
These examples are based on revision 26 31 from r-forge and will not work under earlier revisions (and may not work with later revisions).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>