<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on FOSS Trading</title>
    <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/search/label/Reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on FOSS Trading</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:03:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.fosstrading.com/search/label/Reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning to code is worth it</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2018/08/learning-to-code-is-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2018/08/learning-to-code-is-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone recently shared this great talk by &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitemyapp.com/&#34;&gt;Chris Allen&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://lambdaconf.us/&#34;&gt;lambda conf&lt;/a&gt; 2017.  The title of the talk is &amp;ldquo;Why Johnny Can&amp;rsquo;t Code Good,&amp;rdquo; but the content is more about how to grow as a programmer.  His points are true whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out, or have been coding for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes from Chris&#39; talk are below, in the order they appear in the presentation.  My thoughts are in parentheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s not talking about people who can&amp;rsquo;t code, but rather those who haven&amp;rsquo;t learned to code.  They usually work in the industry, but only know just enough to get things done.  They aren&amp;rsquo;t super-independent, and may have trouble taking on new things.  All of us have been here before (often multiple times in different disciplines; whenever we start something new).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is when you get stuck working on pre-defined tasks in a well-defined space.  The computer science industry&amp;rsquo;s priorities are now wrapped around accommodating people who are comfortable staying there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, nodejs, Go, and other new languages optimize for &amp;ldquo;zero-to-blog&amp;rdquo;, not for something maintainable, or that allows people to build useful abstractions.  There&amp;rsquo;s more focus on what is marketable in a short blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(An interesting point on hiring:) you can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;hire only the best&amp;rdquo;, unless you&amp;rsquo;re able to attract talent. You can&amp;rsquo;t select for it, because other employers trying to &amp;ldquo;hire only the best&amp;rdquo; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using new tools is not learning new skills.  Learning how to learn, without someone feeding you pre-digested material, is how you grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t say something is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s always going to be harder for some, it depends on their context. Either something is worth learning, or it&amp;rsquo;s not. There may be some return-on-investment cutoff point, but it&amp;rsquo;s either worth trying or it&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re an amnesiac culture. We don&amp;rsquo;t remember 5 years ago (and we don&amp;rsquo;t like learning history).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t train how you play. Train harder, be more focused and structured.  (This is a sports analogy. The idea is that you work harder in training than you will work during a game.  That makes the game seem easy.  I have a habit of doing harder things when I&amp;rsquo;m doing something of lesser consequence.  People often asked me how I learned something, and the answer is often &amp;ldquo;I broke something and learned until I understood what I broke and what was needed to fix it.&amp;rdquo;  This is sub-optimal at work, when a faster solution that isn&amp;rsquo;t fully understood is preferable to a slower solution that is.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R/Finance 2014 Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2014/06/rfinance-2014-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2014/06/rfinance-2014-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been more than a month since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/&#34;&gt;R/Finance 2014&lt;/a&gt;, and my job has finally slowed down enough to allow me to write down my thoughts (though I&amp;rsquo;m writing this over two days during my train to and from Chicago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comments below are based on my personal experience. If I don&amp;rsquo;t comment on a seminar or presentation, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it or it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good; it may have been over my head or I may have been distracted with my duties as a committee member. All the currently available conference slides are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/&#34;&gt;on the website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday morning seminar:&lt;br&gt;
I went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/workshop/DirkEddelbuettel.pdf&#34;&gt;Dirk Eddelbuettel&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; seminar because I may be writing a R package to query &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deltixlab.com/&#34;&gt;Deltix&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/null&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deltixlab.com/solutions/timebase.html&#34;&gt;TimeBase&lt;/a&gt; database. Deltix provides a C++ API, so this is a perfect opportunity to use Rcpp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday talks:&lt;br&gt;
The first presentation was given by keynote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/LukeTierney.pdf&#34;&gt;Luke Tierney&lt;/a&gt;, who discussed recent and upcoming performance improvements to R, and introduced some new profiling tools in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ltierney/Rpkg-proftools&#34;&gt;proftools&lt;/a&gt; package (and a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ltierney/Rpkg-proftools-GUI&#34;&gt;proftools-GUI&lt;/a&gt; package).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/YangLu.pdf&#34;&gt;Yang Lu&lt;/a&gt; explored the low-risk anomaly on high/low volatility portfolios with similar industry, size, and volume. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/AveryMoon.pdf&#34;&gt;Avery Moon&lt;/a&gt; discussed how they use R at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wealthfront.com/&#34;&gt;Wealthfront&lt;/a&gt; to run cashflow simulations for their tax-loss harvesting strategy. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/StevenPav.pdf&#34;&gt;Steven Pav&lt;/a&gt; used math and memes to discuss portfolio inference. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/TobiasSetz.pdf&#34;&gt;Tobias Setz&lt;/a&gt; used the Bayesian Change Point method to analyze time series stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/PaulTeetor.pdf&#34;&gt;Paul Teetor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/MatthewClegg.pdf&#34;&gt;Matthew Clegg&lt;/a&gt; discussed different aspects of pairs trading. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/KentHoxsey.pdf&#34;&gt;Kent Hoxsey&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated a simple way to explore trading signal expectation. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/MatthewBarry.pdf&#34;&gt;Matthew Barry&lt;/a&gt; introduced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrbcuda/pbo&#34;&gt;pbo&lt;/a&gt; package, which implements some of the ideas in the paper, &lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2326253&#34;&gt;The Probability of Backtest Overfitting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/AlexiosGhalanos.pdf&#34;&gt;Alexios Ghalanos&lt;/a&gt; was the day&amp;rsquo;s second keynote, and he discussed smooth transition autoregressive models and his new package, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/alexiosg/twinkle&#34;&gt;twinkle&lt;/a&gt;. Alexios &lt;a href=&#34;http://unstarched.net/2014/05/27/twinkletwinkle-little-star/&#34;&gt;wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; discussing his presentation, which you should definitely read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday food/networking:&lt;br&gt;
During the two-hour conference reception at UIC, I had some drinks and hors d&amp;rsquo;ouvres, talked with speakers, and meet people I encouraged to attend and/or present. Next was the (optional) dinner at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trumphotelcollection.com/chicago/rooftop-restaurants-chicago.php&#34;&gt;The Terrace at Trump&lt;/a&gt;. It was cold and windy again this year, so we were inside the entire night. Same as last year, the food was fantastic, but the conversations were even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday talks:&lt;br&gt;
The first presentation was a lightning talk by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/ChiragAnand.pdf&#34;&gt;Chirag Anand&lt;/a&gt;, where he introduced the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/eventstudies/&#34;&gt;eventstudies&lt;/a&gt; package, which is very well done. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/CaseyKing.pptx&#34;&gt;Casey King&lt;/a&gt; gave an incredibly informative and entertaining presentation on anti-money laundering and suspicious activity reporting in penny stocks using message board posts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/BryanLewis.pdf&#34;&gt;Bryan Lewis&lt;/a&gt; introduced his &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bwlewis/IRL&#34;&gt;IRL&lt;/a&gt; package and ran a 16 million node network analysis in &amp;lt; 2 minutes on his Chromebook, during his talk. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/StephenRush.pdf&#34;&gt;Stephen Rush&lt;/a&gt; discussed his work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VPIN&#34;&gt;VPIN&lt;/a&gt; (volume synchronized probability of informed trading), while competing with Steven Pav for the &amp;ldquo;presentation with the most memes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/BobMcDonald.pdf&#34;&gt;Bob McDonald&lt;/a&gt; gave the third keynote presentation, where he discussed using R to teach derivatives in MBA classes. He also explained his decision to adopt R in terms of valuing an option. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/EricZivot.pdf&#34;&gt;Eric Zivot&lt;/a&gt; discussed his upcoming book, &amp;ldquo;Modeling Financial Time Series with S-Plus R&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/RohiniGrover.pdf&#34;&gt;Rohini Grover&lt;/a&gt; measured the imprecision of implied volatility estimates in volatility indexes using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-forge.r-project.org/projects/ifrogs/&#34;&gt;ifrogs&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/BillCleveland.pdf&#34;&gt;Bill Cleveland&lt;/a&gt; gave the final keynote and talked about the &amp;ldquo;divide-and-recombine&amp;rdquo; method for large, complex data, using R and Hadoop. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/GregorKastner.pdf&#34;&gt;Gregor Kastner&lt;/a&gt; introduced his &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/stochvol/&#34;&gt;stochvol&lt;/a&gt; package, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/MatthewDixon.pdf&#34;&gt;Matthew Dixon&lt;/a&gt; showed how to calibrate stochastic volatility models using his &amp;ldquo;alpha&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mfrdixon/gpusvcalibration&#34;&gt;gpusvcalibration&lt;/a&gt; package. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2014/talk/DirkEddelbuettel.pdf&#34;&gt;Dirk Eddelbuettel&lt;/a&gt; closed the conference with a lightning talk on his recently-released &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RcppRedis/&#34;&gt;RcppRedis&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee also presented the awards for best papers. The winners were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portfolio inference with this one weird trick&lt;/em&gt;, Steven E. Pav&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dealing with Stochastic Volatility in Time Series Using the R Package stochvol&lt;/em&gt;, Gregor Kastner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Re-Evaluation of the Low-Risk Anomaly in Finance via Matching&lt;/em&gt;, Yang Lu, Daniel Wu, Kwok Yu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All words are not equal: Sentiment dynamics and information content within CEO letters&lt;/em&gt;, Kris Boudt, James Thewissen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday food/networking:&lt;br&gt;
As always, the conference ended with one more trip to &lt;a href=&#34;http://jakstap.com/&#34;&gt;Jaks Tap&lt;/a&gt;. I spent some time giving college students some advice about starting their careers, and discussed the presentation I gave earlier in the week at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/ChicagoRUG/&#34;&gt;Chicago R User Group&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://files.meetup.com/1625815/ProfilingForSpeed_Ulrich_05-14.pdf&#34;&gt;Profiling for Speed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least: none of this would be possible without the support of fantastic sponsors:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://business.uic.edu/academic-centers-and-research/cba-research-centers/international-center-for-futures-and-derivatives&#34;&gt;International Center for Futures and Derivatives at UIC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revolutionanalytics.com/&#34;&gt;Revolution Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/compfin/&#34;&gt;MS-Computational Finance at University of Washington&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onetick.com/&#34;&gt;OneMarketData&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.org/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://spotfire.tibco.com/&#34;&gt;TIBCO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symmys.com/arpm-bootcamp&#34;&gt;SYMMS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paradigm4.com/&#34;&gt;paradigm4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R/Finance 2013 Review</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2013/05/r-finance-2013-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2013/05/r-finance-2013-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been one week since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/&#34;&gt;5th Annual R/Finance conference&lt;/a&gt;, and I finally feel sufficiently recovered enough to share my thoughts. The conference is a two-day whirlwind of applied quantitative finance, fantastic networking, and general geekery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comments below are based on my personal experience.  If I don&amp;rsquo;t comment on a seminar or presentation, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it or it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good; it may have been over my head or I may have been distracted with my duties as a committee member.  All the currently available conference slides are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/&#34;&gt;on the website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday morning seminar:&lt;br&gt;
I went to (and live-tweeted) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/workshop/JeffRyan.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeff Ryan&amp;rsquo;s seminar&lt;/a&gt; because I wanted to learn more about how he uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/mmap/&#34;&gt;mmap&lt;/a&gt;+&lt;a href=&#34;http://r-forge.r-project.org/projects/indexing&#34;&gt;indexing&lt;/a&gt; with options data.  There I realized that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inside-r.org/r-doc/base/DateTimeClasses&#34;&gt;POSIXlt&lt;/a&gt; components use a zero-based index because they mirror the underlying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cplusplus.com/reference/ctime/tm/&#34;&gt;tm struct&lt;/a&gt;, and that mmap+indexing files can be shared across cores and you can read them from other languages (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday talks:&lt;br&gt;
The first presentation was by keynote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/RyanSheftel.pdf&#34;&gt;Ryan Sheftel&lt;/a&gt;, who talked about how he uses R on his bond trading desk.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/DavidArdia.pdf&#34;&gt;David Ardia&lt;/a&gt; showed how expected returns can be estimated via the covariance matrix.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/RonaldHochreiter.pdf&#34;&gt;Ronald Hochreiter&lt;/a&gt; gave an overview of modeling optimization via his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modopt.com/&#34;&gt;modopt&lt;/a&gt; package.  Tammer Kamel gave a live demo of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quandl.com/help/packages/r&#34;&gt;Quandl package&lt;/a&gt; and said, &amp;ldquo;Quandl hopes to do to Bloomberg what Wikipedia did to Britannica.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of introducing both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/DougMartin.pdf&#34;&gt;Doug Martin&lt;/a&gt;, who talked about robust covariance estimation, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/GilesHeywood.pdf&#34;&gt;Giles Heywood&lt;/a&gt;, who discussed several ways of estimating and forecasting covariance, and proposed an &amp;ldquo;open source equity risk and backtest system&amp;rdquo; as a means of matching talent with capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/RueyTsay.pdf&#34;&gt;Ruey Tsay&lt;/a&gt; was the next keynote, and spoke about using principal volatility components to simplify multivariate volatility modeling.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/AlexiosGhalanos.pdf&#34;&gt;Alexios Ghalanos&lt;/a&gt; spoke about modeling multivariate time-varying skewness and kurtosis.  Unfortunately, I missed both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/KrisBoudt.pdf&#34;&gt;Kris Boudt&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/DavidMatteson.pdf&#34;&gt;David Matteson&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; presentations, but I did get to see Winston Chang&amp;rsquo;s live demo of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.com/shiny/&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday food/networking:&lt;br&gt;
The two-hour conference reception at UIC was a great time to have a drink, talk with speakers, and say hello to people I had never met in person.  Next was the (optional) dinner at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trumphotelcollection.com/chicago/rooftop-restaurants-chicago.php&#34;&gt;The Terrace at Trump&lt;/a&gt;.  Unfortunately, it was cold and windy, so we only spent 15-20 minutes on the terrace before moving inside.  The food was fantastic, but the conversations were even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed the first block of lightning talks.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/Azzarello+Putnam.pdf&#34;&gt;Samantha Azzarello&lt;/a&gt; discussed her work with Blu Putnam, which used a dynamic linear model to evaluate the Fed&amp;rsquo;s performance vis-a-vis the Taylor Rule.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/JiahanLi.pdf&#34;&gt;Jiahan Li&lt;/a&gt; used constrained least squares on 4 economic fundamentals to forecast foreign exchange rates.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/ThomasHarte.pdf&#34;&gt;Thomas Harte&lt;/a&gt; talked about regulatory requirements of foreign exchange pricing (and wins the award for most slides, 270); basically documentation is important, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inside-r.org/r-doc/utils/Sweave&#34;&gt;Sweave&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/SanjivDas.pptx&#34;&gt;Sanjiv Das&lt;/a&gt; gave a keynote on 4 applications: 1) network analysis on SEC and FDIC filings to determine banks that pose systematic risk, 2) determining which home mortgage modification is optimal, 3) portfolio optimization with mental accounting, 4) venture capital communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of introducing the following speakers: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/DirkEddelbuettel.pdf&#34;&gt;Dirk Eddelbuettel&lt;/a&gt; showed how it&amp;rsquo;s easy to write fast linear algebra code with &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RcppArmadillo/index.html&#34;&gt;RcppArmadillo&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/KlausSpanderen.pdf&#34;&gt;Klaus Spanderen&lt;/a&gt; showed how to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://quantlib.org/index.shtml&#34;&gt;QuantLib&lt;/a&gt; from R, and even how to to call C++ from R from C++.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/BryanLewis.pdf&#34;&gt;Bryan Lewis&lt;/a&gt; talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scidb.org/&#34;&gt;SciDB&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/scidb/&#34;&gt;scidb&lt;/a&gt; package (SciDB contains fast linear algebra routines that operate &lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt; the database!).  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/MatthewDowle.pdf&#34;&gt;Matthew Dowle&lt;/a&gt; gave an introduction to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/data.table/index.html&#34;&gt;data.table&lt;/a&gt; (in addition to a seminar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attilio Meucci gave his keynote on visualizing advanced risk management and portfolio optimization.  Immediately following, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/BrianPeterson.pdf&#34;&gt;Brian Peterson&lt;/a&gt; gave a lightning on implementing Meucci&amp;rsquo;s work in R (Attilio works in Matlab), which was part of a Google Summer of Code project last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/Chance+Hanson+etal.pdf&#34;&gt;Thomas Hanson&lt;/a&gt; presented his work with Don Chance (and others) on computational issues in estimating the volatility smile.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rinfinance.com/agenda/2013/talk/JeffRyan.pdf&#34;&gt;Jeffrey Ryan&lt;/a&gt; showed how to manipulate options data in R with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/rgreeks/&#34;&gt;greeks&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference wrapped up by giving away three books, generously donated by Springer, to three random people who submitted feedback surveys.  I performed the random drawing live on stage, using my patent-pending TUMC method (I tossed the papers up in the air).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee also presented the awards for best papers.  The winners were: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regime switches in volatility and correlation of ﬁnancial institutions&lt;/em&gt;, Boudt et. al.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Bayesian interpretation of the Federal Reserve&amp;rsquo;s dual mandate and the Taylor Rule&lt;/em&gt;, Putnam &amp;amp; Azzarello&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonparametric Estimation of Stationarity and Change Points in Finance&lt;/em&gt;, Matteson et. al.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estimating High Dimensional Covariance Matrix Using a Factor Model&lt;/em&gt;, Sun (best student paper)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday food/networking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whirlwind came to a close at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jakstap.com/&#34;&gt;Jaks Tap&lt;/a&gt;.  I was finally able to ask speed-obsessed Matthew Dowle about potential implementations of a multi-type xts object (a Google Summer of Code project this year).    I also spoke to a few people about how to add options strategy backtesting to quantstrat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least: none of this would be possible without the support of fantastic sponsors: &lt;a href=&#34;http://business.uic.edu/academic-centers-and-research/cba-research-centers/international-center-for-futures-and-derivatives&#34;&gt;International Center for Futures and Derivatives at UIC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.revolutionanalytics.com/&#34;&gt;Revolution Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/compfin/&#34;&gt;MS-Computational Finance at University of Washington&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lemnica.com/&#34;&gt;lemnica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opengamma.com/&#34;&gt;OpenGamma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onetick.com/&#34;&gt;OneMarketData&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rstudio.org/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Parallel R</title>
      <link>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2012/06/book-review-parallel-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.fosstrading.com/2012/06/book-review-parallel-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1449309925/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=fotr09-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1449309925&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ws.assoc-amazon.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;amp;ASIN=1449309925&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=fotr09-20&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;You have a problem: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; is single-threaded, but your code would be faster if it could simultaneously run on more than one core.  You have access to a cluster and/or your computer has multiple cores.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1449309925/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=fosstrading-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1449309925&#34;&gt;Parallel R&lt;/a&gt;, by Q. Ethan McCallum and Stephen Weston, can help you put this extra computing power to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book describes 6 approaches to distributed computing.  Thoughts on each approach follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/snow/&#34;&gt;snow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter starts by showing you how to create a socket cluster on a single machine (later sections discuss &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.open-mpi.org/&#34;&gt;MPI&lt;/a&gt; clusters, and socket clusters of several machines).Then a section describes how to initialize workers, with a later section giving a slightly advanced discussion on how functions are serialized to workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a great demonstration (including graphs) of why/when you should use &lt;code&gt;clusterApplyLB()&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;clusterApply()&lt;/code&gt;.  There&amp;rsquo;s also a fantastic discussion on potential I/O issues (probably one of the most surprising/confusing issues to people new to distributed computing) and how &lt;code&gt;parApply()&lt;/code&gt; handles them.  Then the authors provide a very useful &lt;code&gt;parApplyLB()&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few (but very important!) paragraphs on random number generation using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rsprng/index.html&#34;&gt;rsprng&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rlecuyer/index.html&#34;&gt;rlecuyer&lt;/a&gt; packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/multicore/&#34;&gt;multicore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter starts by noting that the multicore package only works on a single computer running a POSIX compliant operating system (i.e. most anything &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; Windows).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section describes the &lt;code&gt;mclapply()&lt;/code&gt; function, and also explains how &lt;code&gt;mclapply()&lt;/code&gt; creates a cluster each time it&amp;rsquo;s called, why this isn&amp;rsquo;t a speed issue, and how it is actually beneficial.  The next few sections describe some of the optional &lt;code&gt;mclapply()&lt;/code&gt; arguments, and how you can achieve load balancing with &lt;code&gt;mclapply()&lt;/code&gt;.  A good discussion of &lt;code&gt;pvec()&lt;/code&gt;, parallel, and collect functions follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some great tips on how to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rsprng/index.html&#34;&gt;rsprng&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/rlecuyer/index.html&#34;&gt;rlecuyer&lt;/a&gt; packages for random number generation, even though they aren&amp;rsquo;t directly supported by the multicore package.  The chapter concludes with a short, but effective, description of multicore&amp;rsquo;s low-level API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parallel (comes with R &amp;gt;= 2.14.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter starts by noting that the parallel package is a combination of the snow and multicore packages.  This chapter is relatively short, since those two packages were covered in detail over the prior two chapters.  Most of the content discusses the implementation differences between parallel and snow/multicore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R+&lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Hadoop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a full chapter primer on Hadoop and MapReduce, for those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the software and concept.  The chapter ends with an introduction to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/&#34;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/elasticmapreduce/&#34;&gt;EMR&lt;/a&gt; services, which significantly lower the barrier to using Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter on R+Hadoop is very little R and mostly Hadoop.  This is because Hadoop requires more setup than the other approaches.  You will need to do some work on the command line and with environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three examples; one Hadoop streaming and two using the Java API (which require writing/modifying some Java code).  The authors take care to describe each block of code in all the examples, so it&amp;rsquo;s accessible to those who haven&amp;rsquo;t written Java.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rhipe.org/&#34;&gt;RHIPE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using three examples, this chapter provides a thorough treatment of how to use RHIPE to abstract-away a lot of the boilerplate code required for Hadoop.  Everything is done in R.  As with the Hadoop chapter, the authors describe each block of code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RHIPE does require a little setup: it must be installed on your workstation and all cluster nodes.  In the examples, the authors describe how RHIPE allows you to transfer R objects between Map and Reduce phases, and they mention the RHIPE functions you can use to manipulate &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HDFS#Hadoop_Distributed_File_System&#34;&gt;HDFS&lt;/a&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/segue/&#34;&gt;segue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very short chapter because the segue package has very narrow scope: using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EMR service in two lines of code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final thoughts:&lt;br&gt;
I would recommend this book to someone who is looking to move beyond the most basic distributed computing solutions.  The authors are careful to point you in the right direction and warn you of potential pitfalls of each approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All but the most basic setups (e.g. a socket cluster on a single machine) will require some familiarity with the command line, environment variables, and networking.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t the fault of the authors or any of the approaches&amp;hellip; parallel computing just isn&amp;rsquo;t that easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really expected to see something on using &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/foreach/&#34;&gt;foreach&lt;/a&gt;, especially since Stephen Weston has done work on those packages.  It is mentioned briefly at the end of the book, so maybe it will appear in later editions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
